{
    "items": [
        {
            "id": "5ea1f712-fc18-40ae-9dc9-89081997310d",
            "question": "What is the maximum number of teams that have played in single edition of IPL?",
            "answer": "10",
            "options": [
                "8",
                "9",
                "10",
                "7"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "1"
        },
        {
            "id": "5588a017-c8e6-4b09-9aea-44322eaf4f88",
            "question": "What name is given to test matches between Australia and England?",
            "answer": "Ashes",
            "options": [
                "Ashes",
                "Border-Gavaskar Trophy",
                "Natwest Series",
                "Commonwealth Bank Series"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "1"
        },
        {
            "id": "86e85994-6e8a-4836-a5bd-2e6bce502ce1",
            "question": "Which player holds the record for highest individual score in a test inning?",
            "answer": "Brian Lara",
            "options": [
                "Brian Lara",
                "Mathew Hayden",
                "Virendra Sehwag",
                "Mahela Jayawardne"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "1"
        },
        {
            "id": "9ccaf561-ca17-4cb4-ad0b-363cb459dcf3",
            "question": "Which team was the first team to win 50 over world cup as host nation?",
            "answer": "Sri Lanka",
            "options": [
                "India",
                "Australia",
                "Sri Lanka",
                "England"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "2"
        },
        {
            "id": "cf021ea9-13d4-44fb-9f57-97b2bc4c9caa",
            "question": "Which bowler has most hat-tricks in ODI cricket?",
            "answer": "Lasith Malinga",
            "options": [
                "Brett Lee",
                "Lasith Malinga",
                "Wasim Akram",
                "Muttiah Muralidaran"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "2"
        },
        {
            "id": "d0cc8e40-c716-4a5e-9471-4ddcc70c39a6",
            "question": "Which indian bowler has best bowling figures in a test inning?",
            "answer": "Anil Kumble",
            "options": [
                "Kapil Dev",
                "Harbhajan Singh",
                "Jasprit Bumrah",
                "Anil Kumble"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "1"
        },
        {
            "id": "92eec856-0f5e-41b8-b845-ec48306ccc8f",
            "question": "Amongst left arm spinners which player has most ODI wickets?",
            "answer": "Sanath Jayasuria",
            "options": [
                "Rangana Herath",
                "Shakib-al-Hasan",
                "Sanath Jayasuria",
                "Nicky Boje"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "3"
        },
        {
            "id": "aafdb6e-a451-4944-ba58-29b563ff416a",
            "question": "Which team finished last in IPL 2009 season?",
            "answer": "KKR",
            "options": [
                "RCB",
                "RR",
                "KKR",
                "KXIP"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "2"
        },
        {
            "id": "88d36a56-d459-4eec-8576-cbeb6f2e7156",
            "question": "Who became the first bowler to take 400 wickets in both tests and OdIs?",
            "answer": "Wasim Akram",
            "options": [
                "Muttiah Muralidaran",
                "Wasim Akram",
                "Glenn Mcgrath",
                "Chaminda Vaas"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "3"
        },
        {
            "id": "068db50d-4cd1-42dc-a674-03bf279ecebc",
            "question": "Which batsman has most runs in ODI cricket without scoring a century?",
            "answer": "Misbah-ul-Haq",
            "options": [
                "Mark Boucher",
                "Heath Streak",
                "Misbah-ul-Haq",
                "Graham Thorpe"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "6"
        },
        {
            "id": "87fba552-f0a2-4933-bd55-193660f6ec34",
            "question": "Who is the only bowler to take a hat-trick on his birthday?",
            "answer": "Peter Siddle",
            "options": [
                "Stuart Broad",
                "Peter Siddle",
                "Lasith Malinga",
                "Jason Gillespe"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "6"
        },
        {
            "id": "277a4661-2cd9-4178-a0d0-8f8b4edd25dc",
            "question": "Who was the captain of indian cricket team, when Sachin Tendulkar was denied a double century as the innings was declared by the then captain?",
            "answer": "Rahul Dravid",
            "options": [
                "Sourav Ganguly",
                "Anil Kumble",
                "Rahul Dravid",
                "MS Dhoni"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "3"
        },
        {
            "id": "4b01fa54-481d-428b-8bf4-01ec4112d44b",
            "question": "Which cricketer holds the record for fastest Indian to 50, 150, 200, 250 ODI wickets?",
            "answer": "Ajit Agarkar",
            "options": [
                "Zaheer Khan",
                "Kapil Dev",
                "Harbhajan Singh",
                "Ajit Agarkar"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "4"
        },
        {
            "id": "ade7e299-b9db-4ee8-9d82-4a8e3f8c4746",
            "question": "Only 3 Indians have batted on all 5 days of test cricket, Ml Jaisimha, Ravi Shastri and one more. Identify the third player.",
            "answer": "Cheteshwar Pujara",
            "options": [
                "Cheteshwar Pujara",
                "VVS Laxman",
                "Ajinkya Rahane",
                "Sachin Tendulkar"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "4"
        },
        {
            "id": "d3ccd757-5a48-4a45-9361-bbd4bfeb6b82",
            "question": "After which year BCCI added ban on players to prevent them in participating in more than 1 u19 world cup?",
            "answer": "2016",
            "options": [
                "2014",
                "2016",
                "2018",
                "2010"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "4"
        },
        {
            "id": "bf4d43ca-4fd6-41e4-9263-ca1f4d844e7b",
            "question": "Name India's domestic 20 over tournament.",
            "answer": "Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy",
            "options": [
                "Vijay Hazare Trophy",
                "Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy",
                "Deodhar Trophy",
                "Ranji Trophy"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "3"
        },
        {
            "id": "d05438df-1168-452f-ab7e-bf393c42238d",
            "question": "Which player has hit most sixes in test cricket?",
            "answer": "Brendon Mccullum",
            "options": [
                "Chris Gayle",
                "Adam Gilchrist",
                "Brendon Mccullum",
                "Virendra Sehwag"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "6"
        },
        {
            "id": "855fecfc-9429-4c75-9f2e-60e9c46c0d30",
            "question": "Name the active player who holds the record for most number of matches without ducks in T20I career.",
            "answer": "David Miller",
            "options": [
                "Eoin Morgan",
                "Quinton De Kock",
                "Tom Latham",
                "David Miller"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "6"
        },
        {
            "id": "b5ccdae9-36b7-47ab-bcfc-789711de276d",
            "question": "Who is the only batsman to have carried his bat through a test innings thrice in his career?",
            "answer": "Dean Elgar",
            "options": [
                "Sunil Gavaskar",
                "Dean Elgar",
                "Justin Langer",
                "Zaheer Abbas"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "6"
        },
        {
            "id": "76532596-06e3-424f-8150-04b40b643a2c",
            "question": "What is the name of trophy of test series between India and Australia?",
            "answer": "Border-Gavaskar Trophy",
            "options": [
                "Ashes",
                "Border-Gavaskar Trophy",
                "Natwest Series",
                "Commonwealth Bank Series"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "1"
        },
        {
            "id": "0fed534f-b7da-4cd8-98f5-46fb4fe035d4",
            "question": "Who is the only player to take a wicket on the 0th delivery of his T20I career?",
            "answer": "Virat Kohli",
            "options": [
                "Aaron Finch",
                "Virat Kohli",
                "Anrich Nortje",
                "Lendl Simmons"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "6"
        },
        {
            "id": "33b7c1f4-c503-4cf5-b5dc-95d9541df891",
            "question": "Which indian player has been a part of a IPL winning team most number of times?",
            "answer": "Rohit Sharma",
            "options": [
                "Rohit Sharma",
                "MS Dhoni",
                "Piyush Chawla",
                "Shane Watson"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "2"
        },
        {
            "id": "ee7f24c3-20fc-4acc-a8fa-c0aaf74dbe15",
            "question": "If every batsman in an innings gets bowled on the first ball, then which batsmen will remain not out at the end of the innings?",
            "answer": "Number 8",
            "options": [
                "Number 2",
                "Number 8",
                "Number 10",
                "Number 11"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "3"
        },
        {
            "id": "a81f7557-d2fe-4f06-a892-d3730561d772",
            "question": "Which Sri Lankan bowler has claimed a hat trick in 2 legal balls?",
            "answer": "Isuru Udana",
            "options": [
                "Chaminda Vaas",
                "Isuru Udana",
                "Lasith Malinga",
                "Akila Dhananjaya"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "4"
        },
        {
            "id": "1aa78fcc-f7ed-408a-91c2-cf2aae144d8e",
            "question": "Who caught Steve Waugh in his last international match?",
            "answer": "Sachin Tendulkar",
            "options": [
                "Anil Kumble",
                "Rahul Dravid",
                "Parthiv Patel",
                "Sachin Tendulkar"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "3"
        },
        {
            "id": "7c4e6adf-34aa-4e67-bc68-9ac56529238e",
            "question": "How many times has India won u19 world cup?",
            "answer": "4",
            "options": [
                "3",
                "5",
                "4",
                "2"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "2"
        },
        {
            "id": "f6da93d5-fbf3-4d70-974b-1c88c479ed2f",
            "question": "What is the term for a batsmen dismissed on very first ball of his innings?",
            "answer": "Golden Duck",
            "options": [
                "King Pair",
                "Golden Duck",
                "Hit Wicket",
                "Diamond Duck"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "1"
        },
        {
            "id": "ed86e98a-ae83-40c3-9f2f-bbf76bbc98fb",
            "question": "Against which team Sachin Tendulkar scored his highest individual score in ODI cricket?",
            "answer": "South Africa",
            "options": [
                "Pakistan",
                "England",
                "Australia",
                "South Africa"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "2"
        },
        {
            "id": "f790ac09-2185-4eb2-b6f0-5855b55028f1",
            "question": "Who was the first concussion substitute in cricket?",
            "answer": "Marnus Labuschagne",
            "options": [
                "Mehidy Hasan",
                "Kl Rahul",
                "Marnus Labuschagne",
                "Taijul Islam"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "4"
        },
        {
            "id": "2f1229ee-e84d-4c55-a8cb-730cf477c551",
            "question": "Shane Warne, Aravinda De Silva and one more player are the only cricketers to be man of the match in semi-final and final of a cricket world cup. Identify the third player.",
            "answer": "Mohinder Amarnath",
            "options": [
                "Sir Clive Lloyd",
                "Wasim Akram",
                "Mohinder Amarnath",
                "Sir Viv Richards"
            ],
            "difficultyLevel": "4"
        }
    ]
}